# RaviTeja Mupparapu (1) Featured

Hyperion Engineer seeking roles in Application Support for Hyperion ESSBASE & Planning, FDMEE, ASO&BSO cubes, Metadata and data loads, Business rules & Calc scripts, Maintenance activities, Enhancements, EPBCS, PBCS, Data Management, Forms & Reports



Current Designation: L2 Hyperion Engineer-IT Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 10 Month(s)

Current Company: NetApp Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Finance]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: L2 Hyperion Engineer, Backup & Restore, EPBCS, PBCS, Data Management, Hyperion Planning, Migration, FDMEE, Forms, Hyperion Reporting, FDM, Hyperion, Essbase, Metadata, ASO, BSO, EAS, EPM, Shared

Services, Security Management, Enhancements, Smartview, Oracle Cloud, LCM

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

# **Summary**

I am totally having 5 years 10 months, in that 3 years of professional experience on Oracle Hyperion Business Intelligence Application Support with strong analytical, reasoning and good interpersonal skills. Expertise in Oracle PBCS, Oracle EPBCS, Hyperion Planning, Hyperion Essbase, Essbase Administration Services(EAS), Hyperion Financial Close Management, Hyperion financial data quality management Enterprise Edition(FDMEE), Hyperion Financial Reporting, Smart View, ASO/BSO Applications, Maxl, MDX, Calc scripts, Hyperion business rules, Dimension build rules, Data load rules, Groovy Rules and FR reports.

# Work Experience

**NetApp** as L2 Hyperion Engineer-IT Feb 2020 to Till Date

Project : NetApp Inc. Client : Internal Project

Role: L2 Hyperion Supportive Engineer

Duration: Feb 2020 - Till now

Description: NetApp, Inc. is an American hybrid cloud data services and data management company headquartered in Sunnyvale, California. It has ranked in the Fortune 500 since 2012. Founded in 1992 with an IPO in 1995. NetApp offers hybrid cloud data services for management of applications and data across cloud and on-premises environments.

#### Responsibilities:

- \* Supported in Cloud Go-live project.
- \* Actively participated in UAT and SIT for migration into Cloud.
- \* Create interfaces using Data Management.
- \* Create data mappings and scheduling jobs in EPBCS.
- \* Performed Data loading through Data management in EPBCS.
- \* Responsible for optimizing the business rules and application performance.
- \* Responsible for Data Backups, Exports & Imports and Migration of Applications in EPBCS.
- \* Solving users reports and group access and SmartView issue.
- \* Conduct training for the end users for SmartView as well as for the application.
- Responsible for security provisioning using shared services across the entire Hyperion environment.

- \* On time completion of all assigned tasks and meeting the business expectations and timelines.
- \* Responsible for Workflow of the Application and Basic security for the users.
- \* Involved in Knowledge transfer and development transition to the other team members.
- \* Actively involved in project development life-cycle from analysis of Functional Specifications Document (requirements gathering), application design, development, testing, rollout into production environment, implementation and end-user training.
- \* Worked Extensively on Shared Services, Essbase applications 11.1.2.3. Performed monthly and quarterly data loads and verifications.
- \* Performed monthly backups of Hyperion data. Helped facilitate the creation and loading of Monthly, quarterly backup data.
- Expertise in Shared services backup by using utilities.

Environment: Oracle PBCS, Oracle EPBCS, Data Management, EPM Automate, Smartview.

### Jp Morgan Chase & Co as Hyperion Consultant

Jan 2018 to Jan 2020

Project: JPMorgan Chase & Co.

Client : Internal Project Role : Hyperion Consultant Duration : Jan 2018- Jan 2020

Description: JPMorgan Chase & Co. is an American multinational investment bank and financial services holding company headquartered in New York City. JPMorgan Chase is ranked by S&P Global as the largest bank in the United States and the sixth largest bank in the world by total assets, with total assets of US\$2.73 trillion. Responsibilities:

- \* Understanding the client's requirement and preparation of the requirement and design document accordingly.
- \* Load metadata for the planning application.
- \* Create planning applications and data forms to allow the end users to enter data as per budgeting process.
- \* Create Menus for Data Forms
- \* Knowledge in Business Rules and Groovy Rules for the Application.
- \* Responsible for Workflow of the Application and Basic security for the users.
- \* Create EPM automate scripts to automate the interfaces
- \* Create interfaces using Data Management
- \* Create data-maps by mapping Smartlist to a dimension in ASO
- Responsible for optimizing the business rules and also application performance
- \* Responsible for Backup and Restore of Application and Migration of Application.
- \* Conduct training for the end users for Smart View as well as for the application.
- \* Post Implementation Support.
- \* Created groups and users for different business segments and then assigned security and filters to define Essbase privileges on them.
- \* Responsible for security provisioning using shared services across the entire Hyperion environment.
- On time completion of all assigned tasks and meeting the business expectations and timelines.
- \* Involved in Knowledge transfer and development transition to the other team members.
- \* Actively involved in project development life-cycle from analysis of Functional Specifications Document (requirements gathering), application design, development, testing, rollout into production environment, implementation and end-user training.
- \* Created reports Using SmartView.
- \* Worked Extensively on Shared Services, Essbase applications 11.1.2.3. Performed monthly and quarterly data loads and verifications.
- \* Performed monthly backups of Hyperion data. Helped facilitate the creation and loading of Monthly, quarterly backup data.
- \* Expertise in Shared services backup by using utilities.

Environment: Oracle PBCS, Oracle EPBCS, Data Management, EPM Automate, Smartview.

### Factset Research Systems as Research Analyst

Mar 2015 to Jan 2018

## **Education**

UG: B.Com (COMPUTERS) from KRISHNA UNIVERSITY in 2013

PG: MBA/PGDM (Finance) from Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan (BVB) in 2015

# IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
MS-OFFICE			
WINDOWS			
Oracle			
SQL Server			
HYPERION WEB ANALYSIS			
Hyperion		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Proficient			
Telugu	Expert			

# **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary Employment Status: Full time